#### Contact

Sec 39 Gurgaon HR +918930068008 (Home) thakurinfotech@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/acharyaks90 (LinkedIn)

www.anilkumarsuryavanshi.wordpres (Blog)

### Top Skills

Generative AI Tools

**ChatGPT** 

Express.js

### Languages

English (Professional Working) Hindi (Native or Bilingual)

#### Certifications

Angular 5 (formerly Angular 2) - The Complete Guide

Automate tasks and processes with Jira

How to use roadmaps in Jira

NodeJS Api Masterclass with Express and Mongo

Build a RESTful API with Node.js, Express and PostgreSQL Training Course completion

#### Honors-Awards

Start Performer of Quarter

On Spot Recognition Certificate of Appreciation

# **Anil Kumar**

Senior Specialist Software Engineering at LTIMINDTREE(Formerly LTI - Larsen & Toubro Infotech) having 12+ Yrs (Angular Advocate) Pune, Maharashtra, India

# Summary

Result oriented individual with superior strengths in utilizing broad experience and creative strategies to facilitate successful completion of corporate objectives. Committed to grow in an organization, this will profitably utilize my talents and energy. Having Experience in Web Development( php, wordpress, JAVA SCRIPT, HTML5, Bootsrap, Angular JS, Jquery), IDE Adobe Dreamweaver, Sublime and Designing Graphics( Vector and Raster Photoshop, Illustrator)

Working with Xchanging Technology India Pvt LTD., Worked with Art Tech Services(Starting Stage), HCL Services LTD for Website and Mobile Development. and IT -Admin( E-commerce and News Portal Website.MicroBlog, Health Care Websites) and System Support

## Experience

**LTIMindtree** 

4 years

Senior Specialist Software Engineering October 2024 - Present (2 months)

Pune, Maharashtra, India

Specialist Software Engineering
December 2020 - October 2024 (3 years 11 months)

Pune, Maharashtra, India

Builder

Senior Software Engineer

October 2019 - December 2020 (1 year 3 months)

Gurgaon, India

Major Worked as Front End Dev( Angular , Typescript) and Minor Backend RubyOnRails

**HTC Global Services** 

3 years 3 months

Senior Software Engineer

2018 - August 2019 (1 year)

Gurgaon, India

Software Engineer

June 2016 - June 2018 (2 years 1 month)

Gurgaon, India

Data Integration (Xchanging Technology)

Software Engineer

August 2015 - August 2016 (1 year 1 month)

**GURGAON** 

Working with Xchanging TechnologyGurgoan India with Angular JS, HTML5, Jquery, Bootsrap

**HCL Infosystems Ltd** 

System Admin

January 2014 - July 2015 (1 year 7 months)

Noida Area, India

Linux Server Support, Ubuntu O.S. Support, PHP MYSQL App Development HTML 5, Angular JS, CSS, Bootstrap, ECOURT - Inidian Judiciary Project

Art Tech Services

Web Developer and IT Admin

September 2012 - October 2013 (1 year 2 months)

- Creating Wireframes.
- Designing Photoshop Web Layout.
- Creating Wordpress theme.
- Creating Web Apps( HTML5, Jquery, Angular JS, PHP, Wordpress, MYSQL, CSS3)
- Take Backup of Website (Server Hosting and Database)
- Networking (LAN,WAN)
- Also Giving Remote support by Team viewer and Real VNC
- · Weekly Preparing Reports.
- Marketing (SMO, SEO)
- Ensuring the Web Security.
- O.S. Installation and Software Installation

# Education

### freeCodeCamp

Full Stack Web Development Certification, Computer Software Engineering · (2016 - 2018)

## MDU ROHTAK

B.TECH, Computer Science · (2008 - 2012)